che.com 1999-04-29

# The McGraw-Hill Companies Customer Privacy Policy

## 

## The McGraw-Hill Companies Customer Privacy Policy

* * *

The McGraw-Hill Companies recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of Personally-Identifiable Information collected about you, our customers and prospects. Personally-Identifiable Information includes your e-mail address, employment status, and "click stream" data which tracks how you use an online service. We have adopted a corporate-wide Customer Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, store and use this Personally-Identifiable Information about our customers and prospects. Our intent is to balance our legitimate business interests in collecting and using this Information against your reasonable expectations of privacy. This Policy includes the following:

**1\. Notice.** We will notify you as to the types of Personally-Identifiable-Information we are collecting about you as well as the uses we intend to make of that Information. For example, we need to collect and store your name, address, and other basic Personally-Identifiable Information to provide you with the service or product you requested and for billing purposes. This Information also enables us to develop and customize products to better meet your needs and preferences and to offer you products from both The McGraw-Hill Companies and other sources that may be of interest to you.

**2\. Collection and Security.** We will only collect this type of Personally Identifiable Information to the extent deemed reasonably necessary to serve our legitimate business purposes and we will maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the Information.

**3\. Opt-Out.** From time to time, we are approached by companies and organizations that produce a product or service that we believe may be of interest to you. We see this as a value-added service helping you to find products or services to help you work or play smarter. We will offer you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your Personally-Identifiable Information shared with parties outside of The McGraw-Hill Companies.

**4\. Sensitive Data.** If your relationship with us includes providing one of the Corporation's business units with Personally-Identifiable Information which is particularly "Sensitive", we will protect that information with extra care. We define Sensitive Data as including Social Security numbers, mother's maiden name, personal financial data such as salary-specific information, specific stock holdings and net worth, information regarding someone's specific medical condition and most information about children. There will be no external distribution of this Sensitive Data outside of The McGraw-Hill Companies. In addition, you may "opt out" of having this information shared among business units within the family of The McGraw-Hill Companies.

**5\. Questions and Concerns?** Each business unit is in the process of designating someone to implement privacy protection for that unit's customers and prospects. You soon will find a contact name listed on each Web site and in many of our print products.

**6\. Review and Correction.** In the near future, you will be able to request a copy of the Personally-Identifiable Information a business unit has collected about you, and request changes if you find it inaccurate.

**To return to your site of origin, please click on the 'Back' button at the top of your browser.**

* * *

Privacy Policy Section The McGraw-Hill Companies Home Page
The McGraw-Hill Companies' Customer Privacy Policy has been developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the finest quality products and services with the highest level of integrity in dealing with our customers. The Policy guides how we collect, store and use information about customers and prospects, and it will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers' changing needs. 

Our Policy recognizes two kinds of personal data that deserve different levels of protection. _Personally-Identifiable Information_ includes, for example, e-mail addresses, billing information, employment status and "click stream" data that tracks visitor activity on a Web site or online service. A subset of that category, Sensitive Data, deserves additional safeguards. _Sensitive Data_ includes, by way of example, Social Security numbers, mothers' maiden names, personal financial data (such as specific salary, portfolio or net worth information), information about specific medical conditions and most information about children. Our business units collect Personally-Identifiable Information and Sensitive Data only when there is a legitimate business need to do so. 

Our Policy provides the following: 

**1\. Notice.** We will inform you about why we are collecting Personally-Identifiable Information and how we intend to use it. We need to collect and store your name, address, and other basic Personally-Identifiable Information, for example, to provide you with the product or service you requested, as well as for billing purposes. This information also enables us to develop and customize products to better meet your needs and preferences and to offer you products from The McGraw-Hill Companies and other sources that may be of interest to you.

**2\. Opt Out.** From time to time, we are approached by companies and organizations that have a product or service that we believe may be of interest to you. We may share your Personally-Identifiable Information with these companies in an effort to help you find these resources. We will, however, offer you the opportunity to "opt out" of having your Personally-Identifiable Information shared with third parties that are not affiliated with The McGraw-Hill Companies. 

If your relationship with us includes providing one of the Corporation's business units with Sensitive Data, we will protect that information with extra care. We will not distribute Sensitive Data outside of the family of The McGraw-Hill Companies, and will give you the chance to opt out of sharing this information within our own organization.

**3\. Security.** We will maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of your Personally-Identifiable Information.

**4\. Review and Correction.** We are continuing to enhance our procedures to enable you to review and correct, upon request, the Personally-Identifiable Information we collect from you. Currently, most of our units require that you make such a request in a manner that can be verified. 

**Questions and comments?** The McGraw-Hill Companies Customer Privacy Policy has been developed out of respect for the privacy preferences and choices of our customers and prospects. We have established procedures to ensure that every reasonable effort is made to address your concerns. Each business unit within The McGraw-Hill Companies has designated a privacy official to implement our Customer Privacy Policy for its respective customers and prospects. You should find contact information on each of our units' Web sites that collect data from you. 

The Corporation also has established a standing Privacy Steering Committee consisting of senior corporate executives and managers from our major business segments. This Committee will continue to oversee implementation of and compliance with our Policy and will adapt the Policy to reflect changes in technology and customer expectations. The co-chairs of the Committee also are charged with handling any unresolved customer concerns. You can reach them by sending an e-mail message to [washaff@mcgraw-hill.com](mailto:washaff@mcgraw-hill.com). 

To ensure that we are following our stated Policy, we also are conducting periodic and random audits of our Web sites and other products and services. The results of our review are shared with senior management and our Board of Directors. A report of our experience will be available in 1999. 

* * *

Privacy Policy Section The McGraw-Hill Companies Home Page
The McGraw-Hill Companies' Customer Privacy Policy has been developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the finest quality products and services with the highest level of integrity in dealing with our customers. The Policy guides how we collect, store and use information about customers and prospects, and it will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers' changing needs. 

Our Policy recognizes two kinds of personal data that deserve different levels of protection. _Personally-Identifiable Information_ includes, for example, e-mail addresses, billing information, employment status and "click stream" data that tracks visitor activity on a Web site or online service. A subset of that category, Sensitive Data, deserves additional safeguards. _Sensitive Data_ includes, by way of example, Social Security numbers, mothers' maiden names, personal financial data (such as specific salary, portfolio or net worth information), information about specific medical conditions and most information about children. Our business units collect Personally-Identifiable Information and Sensitive Data only when there is a legitimate business need to do so. 

Our Policy provides the following: 

**1\. Notice.** We will inform you about why we are collecting Personally-Identifiable Information and how we intend to use it. We need to collect and store your name, address, and other basic Personally-Identifiable Information, for example, to provide you with the product or service you requested, as well as for billing purposes. This information also enables us to develop and customize products to better meet your needs and preferences and to offer you products from The McGraw-Hill Companies and other sources that may be of interest to you.

**2\. Opt Out.** From time to time, we are approached by companies and organizations that have a product or service that we believe may be of interest to you. We may share your Personally-Identifiable Information with these companies in an effort to help you find these resources. We will, however, offer you the opportunity to "opt out" of having your Personally-Identifiable Information shared with third parties that are not affiliated with The McGraw-Hill Companies. 

If your relationship with us includes providing one of the Corporation's business units with Sensitive Data, we will protect that information with extra care. We will not distribute Sensitive Data outside of the family of The McGraw-Hill Companies, and will give you the chance to opt out of sharing this information within our own organization.

**3\. Security.** We will maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of your Personally-Identifiable Information.

**4\. Review and Correction.** We are continuing to enhance our procedures to enable you to review and correct, upon request, the Personally-Identifiable Information we collect from you. Currently, most of our units require that you make such a request in a manner that can be verified. 

**Questions and comments?** The McGraw-Hill Companies Customer Privacy Policy has been developed out of respect for the privacy preferences and choices of our customers and prospects. We have established procedures to ensure that every reasonable effort is made to address your concerns. Each business unit within The McGraw-Hill Companies has designated a privacy official to implement our Customer Privacy Policy for its respective customers and prospects. You should find contact information on each of our units' Web sites that collect data from you. 

The Corporation also has established a standing Privacy Steering Committee consisting of senior corporate executives and managers from our major business segments. This Committee will continue to oversee implementation of and compliance with our Policy and will adapt the Policy to reflect changes in technology and customer expectations. The co-chairs of the Committee also are charged with handling any unresolved customer concerns. You can reach them by sending an e-mail message to [washaff@mcgraw-hill.com](mailto:washaff@mcgraw-hill.com). 

To ensure that we are following our stated Policy, we also are conducting periodic and random audits of our Web sites and other products and services. The results of our review are shared with senior management and our Board of Directors. A report of our experience will be available in 1999. 

* * *

Privacy Policy Section The McGraw-Hill Companies Home Page
